Dear fellow practitioners, from now on,
Kính thưa các quý đạo hữ từ nay trở đi
all the programs that the
thì tất cả các chương trình mà tu tập
club initiates to commemorate the
phát động của câu lạc bộ về kỷ niệm
important events of the Buddhas,
những cái sự kiện trọng đại của chư Phật
Bodhisattvas, and patriarchs will
Bồ tát với lại các đức tổ sư thì chúng
have three parallel programs:
ta đều có ba chương trình song song thứ
firstly, chanting sutras, listening to Dharma teachings, and meditating; secondly, making
nhất là tụng kinh nghe pháp ngồi thiền
vows to practice the Eight Precepts; and
thứ hai là phát nguyện tu Bát Quan Trai
thirdly, offering alms. The
thứ ba là cúng thí được được cúng
reason we are expanding this this year is
thí vì sao mà năm nay chúng ta được mở
because a large number of our Buddhists
rộng như vậy vì số đông các phật tử của
have made vows to attain Bodhi and practice the Six Harmonies, and
chúng ta đã phát nguyện Bồ Đề tu Lục Hòa
have understood the merits of the Six Harmonies.
đã hiểu được công đức Lục Hòa rồi cho
Therefore, our club has
nên câu lạc bộ của chúng ta có những cái
certain capabilities, dear fellow practitioners. The
năng lực nhất định các quý Đạ Hữu ạ Cái
Six Harmonies practice has a
pháp Lục Hòa đấy nó có cái năng lực nhất
certain power, so we must use
định cho nên chúng ta phải mang cái năng
this power to benefit sentient beings.
lực này đi làm lợi ích cho chúng sinh
If we didn't have anything from the beginning,
Còn nếu như từ đầu chúng ta chưa có cái
we wouldn't dare to make
gì thì chúng ta không dám đâu cúng thí
alms; it's a very difficult task, dear fellow practitioners.
thực là một việc rất khó các quý đạo hữu
Those sentient beings are very difficult to
những chúng sinh đó thì rất khó để mà có
help. But if we have
thể giúp cho họ được Nhưng nếu mình có
the merits of Bodhi and the Six Harmonies, and we
công đức bồ đề công đức Lục Hòa mình hồi
dedicate them to them, they will also receive
hướng cho họ thì họ cũng được những cái
certain benefits. They will have the opportunity.  We are
lợi ích nhất định Họ được cái duyên kết
united with the Six Harmonies, and that
duyên với lại pháp Lục Hòa và cái đó là
benefits all sentient beings. Those
lợi ích cho chúng
who diligently practice the Six Harmonies are
những ai tinh tấn thực hành Lục Hòa thì
all within the Bodhi mind,
người đó đều nằm ở trong tâm bồ đề các
dear fellow practitioners. Think of the
quý đạo hữu ạ Hãy nghĩ đến chúng sinh
suffering of sentient beings and practice the Six Harmonies; that is
khổ để mà thực hành đục Hòa cái đấy vô
extremely beneficial. Because the mind that illuminates the Six Harmonies is the
cùng lợi ích vì tâm chiếu Hoàn quán là
one who practices them, so the mind that
người thực hành Lục Hòa cho nên tâm
illuminates the Six Harmonies sees that its voice is
chiếu Hàn quán thấy rằng tiếng nói của
very valuable to the spiritual realm. The mind that illuminates the Six Harmonies and the physical form of the fellow
mình rất có giá trị đối với lại cõi tâm
practitioners are the
linh Mà Tâm Chú Hoàn quán với các quý
same. Before, the difference was in the
nhau lúc trước thì nó khác nhau ở cái
spirit of practicing the Six Harmonies, and now
tinh thần thực hành Lục Hòa và bây giờ
it is the same in the mind that practices the
nó trùng như nhau ở cái tâm thực hành
Six Harmonies. Each person has a
lục hỏa có mỗi mỗi người mỗi Nhiệm vụ
different task, a higher or lower level. But
khác nhau cao thấp khác nhau thôi còn
if we practice the Six Harmonies with the spirit,
nếu chúng ta với tinh thần thực hành độc
we all generate the merit of the
Hòa Chúng ta đều sản sinh sinh ra Công
Six Harmonies. Do you understand? Therefore, when we praise each other, we also receive great blessings. The merit of the Six Harmonies
công đức lục hỏa ấ thì cái công đức lục
will manifest as enlightenment,
hàa nó sẽ biến hiện ra sự giác ngộ hóa
resolving resentments and delusions
giải những cái oán kết những cái si mê
for sentient beings. That is the benefit.
cho chúng sinh đấy là lợi ích vì thế cho
Therefore...  During the founding days
nên là trong những cái ngày phát động
of this club, the practice of
của câu lạc bộ này thì tâm chếu hoàn
having eight sons was initiated
quán phát động cho Tu thêm bát con trai
to increase merit and
để tăng thêm phần công
virtue. In this practice of having eight sons,
đức thế và trong tu B con trai này thì
we can fully practice and practice with joy,
chúng ta được tu đầy đủ và tu tùy hỉ để
suitable for Buddhist practitioners who still work.
phù hợp với việc mà phật tử chúng ta còn
Even while working,
đi làm nhá Còn công tác còn lao động
we can still practice. Furthermore,
chúng ta vẫn tu được ngoài ra thì cái
this practice of having eight sons
việc tu bát con trai này nó làm cho
increases our blessings and
chúng ta tăng thêm phần Phước báo và trí
wisdom. Therefore,
tuệ thế cho nên là chúng ta tu thứ nữa
we practice again by offering food to the hungry spirits
chúng ta lại thực hành cúng thí thực nữa
to increase the blessings of our fellow practitioners.
để cho cái Phước báo của các đạo hữu
The goal is
được tăng thêm cái mục đích làm sao mà
to help our fellow practitioners reduce
để cho các quý đạo hữu giảm thiểu được
karmic obstacles and increase their merit and
nghiệp chướng tăng được thật nhiều công
blessings.
đức Phước báo cho
Because blessings are the root of life;
mình Tại vì cái Phước nó là gốc cuộc đời
we suffer so much and have so much
này chúng ta quá khổ quá quá nhiều
karma. Therefore, in
nghiệp luôn các quý đạo hữu ạ Cho nên là
many lifetimes we have created karmic obstacles, so in this life we
nhiều kiếp chúng ta gây tạo nghiệp
must
chướng rồi cho nên kiếp lại phải tích
actively strive to accumulate merit and blessings to
cực nỗ lực Tích tập công đức Phước báo
counteract that karmic force,
để còn mà chống đỡ với cái nghiệp lực
and it will form the foundation for our progress
đấy rồi nó làm nền tảng cho chúng ta
in future lives. Is
tinh tấn trong các kiếp sau có đúng
n't that right, fellow practitioners?
không các quý đạo hữu thì cái cái đấy
No one gives us that.  You have to work for yourself,
không ai cho mình được phải tự mình lao
gather your own merits, practice your virtues, cultivate wisdom, and practice morality. Is
động thôi tự mình Thu tập tự mình hành
n't that right, dear fellow practitioners? No one can give you anything.
không các quý đạo hữu làm gì Ai cho mình
Whether it's the Buddha, your teacher, your
được đâu Dù phật hay là dù thầy hay là
master, or the monks, they can only give
dù sư phụ hay là Chư tăng cũng chỉ cho
you knowledge.
mình kiến thức thôi còn tự bản thân mình
You have to do it yourself. That knowledge is
mình phải làm chứ còn kiến thức đấy
like going to school. The teacher
giống như một các anh đi học ấy Cô giáo
gives you knowledge, but if you don't do your homework, you'll fail and remain ignorant.
cho kiến thức mà không chịu làm bài thì
You have to be diligent, but if you
cũng đúp thôi cũng dốt thôi phải quý đ ư
don't want to learn, they'll have to be coaxed. So
không chịu học cũng dỗ thôi cho nên câu
this year, the club will create
lạc bộ năm nay sẽ tạo điều kiện rất rất
many opportunities for us to accumulate merit and
nhiều để cho chúng ta tích lũy các công
blessings to counteract
đức Phước báo chống đỡ với nghiệp lực
karmic forces, so that we can progress. As for how
nhá Để rồi Tăng Tiến đi lên Thế còn ai
far you can practice, you can practice; there's no coercion. This
tu được tới đâu thì tu không bắt ép Đây
is a general rule: today, with mindful contemplation,
là một quy định chung hôm nay tâm chiếu
whoever practices for the required number of days (this
quán nhác này ai tu tập đủ số ngày đây
is just practice). Once you've practiced for the required number of days
là tu tập thôi nhá tu tập đủ số ngày
according to the program, we invite the spirits
theo chương trình thì mời các vong linh
from within to come to the earthly altar. Dear fellow
ở trong đó về đàn trần tế Kính thưa quý
practitioners, we don't have much money;
đạo hữu tiền chúng ta không có nhiều
we must have merit and a Bodhi mind to invite the spirits to the
đề trong đấy chúng ta thỉnh các chúng về
earthly altar. Using money won't do it.
đàn trần tế mới được chứ Dùng tiền thì
There are very few spirits, but many. Is
không có đâu Ít thền lắm mà nhiều vong
n't that right, dear fellow practitioners? That
linh Mà có đúng không quý đạo hữu cho
's why we must practice for a full day. Because when we
nên Tại sao chúng ta phải tu đủ ngày vì
practice for a full day, we have the power and
tu đủ ngày chúng ta có nguyện lực có
diligence within us. Only then can we
tinh tấn ở trong đấy thế chúng ta mới
invite them
thỉnh họ về chúng ta mới có cái chúng ta
back, only then can we dedicate the merit to them. Isn't that right, dear fellow
hồi hướng cho họ chứ có đúng không quý
practitioners? Only then can we invite them. So, as for the eightfold
đạo hữu mới Thỉnh được đấy thế cho nên
practice, sons can do as they please, offering food and alms as they wish. Sons can
thí thực thì tùy ý tu bát Con trai tu
practice if they want, or not if they don't. Of course, if we practice more, the portion of merit dedicated to the spirits will increase, right, dear fellow practitioners? But I'm afraid many of you won't be able to practice, so let's just
không thực hành được cho nên là thôi cứ
leave it as it is. Next year, when we can
để mở ra như thế còn sang năm chúng ta
practice more, we
thực hành được nhiều hơn thì chúng ta
will have to make it mandatory to practice the eightfold practice,
phải bắt buộc phải tu bát con cha có
right? But this year, let's take it
đúng không Nhưng mà năm nay thôi cứ từ
slowly. Let's gradually improve our diligence little by little.
từ dần dần đã Cứ từ từ gọi là tinh tấn
Then we must chant scriptures,
từng phần một Đã thế thì phải tụng kinh
listen to Dharma teachings, and meditate to expand our wisdom.
nghe pháp ngồi thiền để mở mang trí tuệ
We must have the power of diligence to seek enlightenment so that we can have something to
ta phải có thì chúng ta mới có có cái mà
say to those spirits and
mà nói với các cõi vong linh ấy được mà
encourage them.  Is it possible to dedicate the merit to them,
sách tấn họ được mà hồi hướng cho họ
esteemed fellow practitioners?
được có đúng không các quý đạo hữu mình
We don't have the means to do that, do we?
không có mình cho làm sao được nhá Thế
Therefore, practicing chanting, listening to Dharma, and
cho nên tu tụng kinh nghe pháp ngồi
meditating must be done for a sufficient number of days. As for chanting,
thiền phải đủ số ngày thế còn tụng kinh
listening to Dharma, and meditating, we
nghe pháp ngồi thiền ấy thì chúng ta
can make up for it, but only during the initial
được tu bù nhưng tu bù chỉ trong thời
stages of practice,
gian phát động tu tập thôi chứ không
not later.
phải tu bù trong thời gian sau th quý đ
Remember, esteemed fellow practitioners, once we have completed the practice, we can dedicate the merit
Hậu Hữu nhớ nhá chúng ta tu đủ như thế
to the
là chúng ta sẽ được hồi hướng cho vong
departed souls. Respectfully, esteemed fellow practitioners, each practice program has its own meaning. For example, in this program commemorating the Buddha's renunciation, we
niệm Đức Phật xuất gia này thì chúng ta
will diligently practice and
sẽ do chúng ta tu tập tinh tấn như thế
dedicate the merit to the departed
thì chúng ta sẽ hồi hướng cho các vong
souls of our ancestors from many
linh ban gia chí chủ của chúng ta nhiều
lifetimes. We hindered them from renouncing the world and
kiếp chúng ta đã cản trở người ta xuất
practicing the Buddha's true Dharma.
gia tu theo chính pháp của Phật rồi đôi
Sometimes we also have negative karma that
khi mình cũng có những cái nghiệp vào
destroys practitioners, right?
phá hoại người tu phải không Người ta
When people are practicing, we use
đang tu thì mình dùng những cái vô minh
our ignorance to persuade
của mình để khiến cho người ta khuyên
them in various ways to abandon the path of
bảo đủ cách để cho người ta bỏ con đường
practice. That is a very silent sin.
tu cái tội đấy là tội rất lặng thế cho
Therefore, now we must use our hearts to
nên bây giờ mình phải lấy cái tâm tán
praise this practice of renunciation.
thán việc tu xuất gia này đầy đủ các thứ
We need to have all the necessary merits and blessings to
mình mới đủ được công Đức Phước báo mới
have the right mindset to repent of our sins, is
đủ được cái tâm để mà sám hối tội đấy có
n't that right, dear fellow practitioners? Merits and
đúng không quý đạo hữu công đức Phước
blessings must be present. So
báo nó phải có mới được đó nhá Thế rồi
now, when we practice,
bây giờ thì khiến cho mình tu thì đầu óc
our minds are filled with wandering thoughts, unable to think clearly, and
mình là cứ vọng tưởng không tư duy được
many things interfere and hinder our practice.
nhiều thứ nó cứ xen vào nó cản trở mình
Therefore, we must practice
không tu được thì chúng ta phải phải tu
to dedicate the merits. During
để mà hồi hướng nhá trong những cái ngày
these days of practice, the mind is focused on the precepts. We've already set the
tu này thì tâm chiếu Hàn quá đã định
date for the Eight Precepts practice.
luôn ra ngày tu Bát Quan Trai luôn rồi
Now, there's no need for the Dharma centers to discuss and agree on the date for the
Bây giờ không cần các đạo tràng bàn bạc
Eight Precepts practice
rồi thống nhất ngày tu B bát quan trai
anymore; it would waste the time of the
nữa nó sẽ mất thời gian của ban cán sự
Dharma center's leadership. So, we've set a common date for the Eight Precepts practice
đạo tràng cho nên ấn định luôn ngày tu
for the club from now
Bát Quan Trai chung của câu lạc bộ từ
on. All programs will have a
laay trở đi tất cả các chương trình đều
fixed date for the Eight Precepts practice
ấn định luôn ngày tu bát con trai luôn
within the Dharma center. Those who can
thì ở trong đạo tràng Ai đăng ký được tu
complete the practice on the required days can do so, and those who can choose to practice according to their circumstances
đủ thì tu mà ai đăng ký tu tùy duyên thì
can register with the club. Those who
Tu sẽ đăng ký lên câu lạc bộ còn lại tu
can't complete the required
ngoài hai cái ngày đấy Không tu đủ số
days can register at the Dharma center. Those who can't complete the required days can register with the
ngày không Tu Đúng ngày thì đăng ký ở
club. Those who can
đạo tràng nhe các quý đạo hữu nhá Còn Tu
complete the required days can register with the Dharma center.
Đúng ngày tu đủ số ngày thì đăng ký lên
For example, if the meditation group has 20
câu lạc bộ Ví dụ đạo tràng là có 20
people practicing, write
người tu thì ghi lên
[music]
[âm nhạc]
I
đó I